Guide to the Ved Mehta Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 1996 Acquisition, circa 1924-1995; 68.25; (122 boxes)
  - Writings and Research Files
    - Up At Oxford material / Various Oxford
      - Checking: Oxford 1957-58
        - Correspondence w/Alistair McCann, 1956 (Box 41)
        - Voltaire Society, 1956-57 (Box 41)
        - Distinguished Raj figures who attended Balliol, 1956 (Box 41)
      - Checking: Oxford 1956-57
        - Rhodes scholarship, 1955-56 (Box 41)
        - Graduate school and fellowships, 1956 (Box 41)
        - Oxford Admission Winter-Spring, 1956 (Box 41)
        - Checking Oxford Courtney Smith (Box 41)
        - Rhodes and other scholarships, Oxford, 1955-56 (Box 41)
        - Oxford/Rhodes (Box 41)
        - Rhodes (Box 41)
        - Educational fund, Hazen, General, 1955-56 (Box 41)
        - Balliol (Box 41)
        - Hazen: Meeting with Braisted (Box 42)
        - Hazen: Grant of award and determination of dollar amount (Box 42)
        - Hazen: reactions to news/ postponement of Harvard (Box 42)
        - Checking: Correspondence Grad school/ Hazen/Oxford, 1955-56 (Box 42)
        - Baedeker (Box 42)
      - Checking Materials- Miscellaneous files
        - Checking: Edward R. Murrow and McCarthy hearings (Box 42)
        - Checking: Gleason lecture (Box 42)
        - Checking: Edward R. Murrow (Box 42)
        - Checking: correspondence, 1953 (Box 42)
        - Checking: Daddyji's radio interview, 1952 (Box 42)
        - "Love Children" material for checking (Box 42)
        - Checking: Young Men's Dreams (Box 42)
    - Babuji (Melissa)
      - Babuji--Overflow? (to be integrated into new book) (Box 42)
      - Babuji: facts/letters, Moore's Family Medicine (Box 42)
      - Babuji Checking--mostly spelling, 1976 (Box 42)
      - Babuji--Tragedies of my life (checking and notes), 1962? (Box 42)
      - Babuji Party Politics (checking and notes), 1960 (Box 42)
      - Babuji Philosophy of End of Life/ Superstition (notes), 1960's (Box 42)
      - Anne Kimbell Relph (Box 42)
      - Babuji: Red Tape (Walkways) notes, 1961 (Box 42)
      - Babuji: The Two Circles (letter from Uma) (Box 43)
      - Babuji and the Arya Samaj (Dead), 1940 (Box 43)
      - Babuji: Red tape (letter writing), 1960 (Box 43)
    - Rajiv Gandhi (EW)
      - Copies of newspaper cuttings/ personal conversation (Moni Malhoutra), 1980's-90's? (Box 43)
      - Moni--India Peace (Box 43)
      - Typing? (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi--gen. elections, 1993 (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi miscellaneous (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi checking (Harshad Mehta), 1992-93 (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi (Bhopal and Bofors), 1992-93 (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi Checking--Economy, 1993 (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi Checking (Punjab and Shir? Sena), 1992-93 (Box 43)
      - Corrections to Rajiv M.S. Salman Haidar, May 1993 (Box 43)
      - Amartya Sen: "The Idea of India" Nehru Lectures (revision) (Box 43)
      - R. Gandhi M.S. Revisions by Malhoutra (and excerpts from Prem Shankar Jha), 1993 (Box 43)
      - Harish Khare update (dead) (Box 43)
      - Rajiv checking--"Blossoms in the Dust" by Kusum Nair, 1961? (Box 43)
      - Indian articles--Discard?, 1989-91 (Box 43)
      - India clippings, 1985, 88-89; 3 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous files
      Includes correspondence.
      - Reserve Bank of India (Box 44)
      - Pomona College, 1972 (Box 44)
      - Articles, correspondence, 1993 (Box 44)
      - Journal introduction, 1952 (Box 44)
      - Articles, 1976-86 (Box 44)
      - Articles, Britannica (Box 44)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation (Box 44)
      - Immigration/Naturalization (Box 44)
      - Mr. Shawn, 1959-1964 (Box 44)
      - Mr. Shawn, 1965-1991; 7 (Box 45)
      - Letter to Amolak Ram, 1924 (copy), undated (Box 45)
      - Cosmopolitan Club Material, 1940 (transcript), undated (Box 45)
      - Watumull file 1957 (copies), undated (Box 46)
      - Watumull file extra copy (checking) (copies), undated (Box 46)
      - Letters 1954 (copies), undated (Box 46)
      - Daulat Ram's (father's brother) 1920 letter, gift from him when Ved was leaving for U.S (Box 46)
      - Lahore Life Victoriana, c. 1930 (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Delhi - Simla Job Sur Fazli-Hussain (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Daddyji - Hayman group, 1931 (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Hayman group discourtesy to the viceroy c. 1935 (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Dr. Atta the dentist, 1950s (Box 46)
      - Salim's Influence Cards, tennis, racing, 1918-47. (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Retirement friendship 1952 (miscellaneous notes and corrections by father) (Box 46)
      - Babuji's children, 1947 (Box 46)
      - Daddyji Rockefeller fellow, 1923 (Box 46)
      - Atlantic Monthly/Face-to-Face/Young Men's Dreams (photocopy), 3 (Box 46)
    - Rajiv Gandhi and Rama's Kingdom
      - 1st version MS, March, 1993 (Box 47)
        "New Yorker pieces scanned, cross-referenced by E. Wagner."
      - Original galleys of New Yorker pieces (Box 47)
      - Personal MS, "Basically first version", 1993 (Box 47)
      - Personal MS, 1993 May (Box 47)
      - Personal MS, "Ms. Gould's changes circa May 4 and May 18 and copy of note from Ms. Gould", 1993 (Box 47)
      - Personal MS, 1993 June (Box 48)
      - Personal MS (incomplete), summer, 1993 (Box 48)
      - Ms. Gould's fixes, 1993 July (Box 48)
    - Portrait of India
      - Proofs, undated; 2 (Box 49)
      - Manuscript, Miss Sargent's copy, undated; 2 (Box 49)
    - Face to Face
      - Manuscript (Box 49)
      - Manuscript, 6 (Box 50)
      - Manuscript, 3 (Box 51)
      - Proofs, 1957; 2 (Box 51)
      - Manuscript, 3 (Box 52)
      - Printed material, 1970s-1980s (Box 52)
    - Various writings
      - Proofs of New Yorker articles, 1985 (Box 53)
      - A Family Affair - Manuscripts and proofs returned by the publishers, 1982; 4 (Box 53)
      - Mahatma Gandhi material (setting copy), 6 (Box 54)
      - Mamaji (setting copy and proof), 5 (Box 55)
      - Portrait of India material (book proofs and setting copy), 6 (Box 56)
    - Indian Journal
      - Manuscript Part I, undated (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part II, undated; 3 (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part III, undated (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part IV, undated; 3 (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part V, undated; 2 (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part VI (empty folder), undated (Box 57)
      - Manuscript Part VII, undated (Box 58)
      - Manuscript Part VIII, undated; 2 (Box 58)
    - Mamaji Manuscript
      - Part I, 1978? (Box 58)
      - Part II, undated (Box 58)
      - Part IIIa, undated (Box 58)
      - Part IIIb, undated (Box 58)
      - Dead pages of manuscript (pages with corrections from Daddyji were substituted for these pages), undated (Box 59)
      - Original manuscripts returned by Mr. Shawn after publication (photographs of Chachaji, etc.), 1979-80; 3 (Box 59)
      - Original manuscripts returned by Mr. Shawn ( New India, etc), 1975 (Box 59)
      - Original manuscripts returned by Mr. Shawn after publication, 1978-79; 2 (Box 60)
      - Original manuscripts returned by Mr. Shawnn after publication (family, etc), 1981-83; 3 (Box 60)
      - Penguin material and correspondence, 1955-56, 63 (Box 61)
      - Personal history/sources, miscellaneous; 4 (Box 61)
    - Up at Oxford (continued)
      - Up at Oxford Proofs returned by Norton, 1993?; 3 (Box 62)
      - Up at Oxford Confirmation Proofs returned by Norton, 1993?; 3 (Box 62)
      - Oxford Book: Shawn's manuscript, returned 11/13/91, 2 (Box 63)
      - Oxford Book - Jasper's corrections on his chapter (Box 63)
      - Uncorrected proof - bound (Box 63)
      - Up at Oxford, draft, printout of 1/12/1993, 2 (Box 63)
      - Up at Oxford, proofs 3/12/93 and 4/22/93, 1993; 5 (Box 64)
      - Penultimate Ms of Oxford book, 3 (Box 65)
      - Last chapter of Oxford book, accepted by Gottlieb, killed by Tina Brown. New Yorker proofs of the article (Box 65)
    - Blackwell's
      - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 65)
      - Proofs, 1960s (Box 65)
      - Amplification, 1960s (Box 66)
      - Reaction to "profile", 1960s (Box 66)
      - Draft, typescript, 1960s (Box 66)
    - Narayan
      - Manuscript, 1960s (Box 66)
      - Proofs, 1960s (Box 66)
      - Correspondence, 1961-62 (Box 66)
    - History [of British historians?]
      - Arrangements of Interviews and Reactions of Subjects, 1961-63 (Box 66)
      - History Correspondence--General Reactions, 1962-63 (Box 66)
      - Young Man's Dream
        - Young Man's Dream: correspondence Anthology of essays by contemporaries Not published (Box 66)
        - Manuscript, unpublished (Box 66)
    - Articles and Stories (continued)
      - Article: Indian Summer, libel correspondence, 1960 (Box 67)
      - Article: Reading on record: notes and materials, 1950s (Box 67)
      - Recordings: Saturday Review Article, 1950s (Box 67)
      - Articles: Manuscripts (published), 1956-1961 (Box 67)
      - Articles: Manuscripts (published), 1961-1969 (Box 67)
      - Stories: Manuscripts (published), 1960-1969; 2 (Box 67)
    - Theology/Philosophy correspondence
      - Theology - correspondence, 1960s; 2 (Box 67)
      - Philosophy: correspondence, arrangement of interviews, 1960 (Box 67)
      - Obituary of Barbara Creaturo, 1990 (Box 67)
      - Philosophy: Correspondence with subjects, 1960s (Box 67)
      - Philosophy: Correspondence reactions, 1960s (Box 67)
      - Philosophy: correspondence: Gellner, 1960s (Box 67)
    - Face to Face
      - Script of BBC adaptation (dramatized version) November 5, 1958 (Box 67)
      - Typed manuscript of BBC adaptation, 1958 (Box 67)
      - Face to Face (1 of 2), 1958; 1; 00:28:42 (Box 122, Item barcode 39002099360928)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Face to Face (2 of 2), 1958; 1; 00:14:45 (Box 122, Item barcode 39002099360936)
    - Chachaji manuscript
      - "The Making of Chachaji," typescript (copy), undated; 2 (Box 67)
    - India Journal: Notes
      - Insert pages in Bhiail notes (series L) (Box 67)
      - Mehta Personal History: manuscript for Vedi I-II, typescript, 1981; 3 (Box 67)
      - Letter from New Delhi, typescripts, 1977, 1981; 2 (Box 67)
    - Ved Mehta Family - original manuscripts returned by Mr. Shawn after publication, 1980s; 2 (Box 68)
      "Ran November 15 and 22, 1982."
    - Photos/reviews - various VM works, 1989, undated (Box 68)
    - New Yorker proofs, undated; 2 (Box 68)
    - Sound-shadows of the New World
      - Correspondence, publicity, etc., 1980s (Box 68)
      - Contracts, 1980s (Box 68)
      - Flap copy, 1980s (Box 68)
      - Production, 1980s (Box 68)
      - Publicity, 1980s (Box 68)
      - Party, 1980s (Box 68)
      - Personal History: The Rich are Different Manuscript, undated (Box 68)
      - Personal History: The Hungry Eye Manuscript, undated; 2 (Box 68)
      - Manuscript: Oxford? Personal History, third revise, Ms. Gould to read, 1986; 4 (Box 68)
      - Manuscript: Personal History, for Mr. Shawn, undated; 2 (Box 68)
    - Rajiv Gandhi & Rama's Kingdom
      - Material returned by Yale University Press: disk, 1994
        1 computer disk
        Available through Access Services (Disk #8).
      - Material returned by Yale University Press: proofs, 1994 (Box 68)
      - Material returned by Yale University Press: photographs, 1994, undated (Box 69)
      - Material returned by Yale University Press: proofs, 1994; 2 (Box 69)
    - The Stolen Light
      - Face to Face: Mr. Shawn's edited copy, 1988 (Box 69)
      - A Love Letter: Mr. Shawn's edited copy, 1988 (Box 69)
      - The Hungry Eye: Mr. Shawn's edited copy, 1988 (Box 69)
      - Autobiographical series -Duplicate copy Daddyji, 1951; 2 (Box 69)
    - New Theologian
      - Manuscript, 1965; 2 (Box 69)
      - Proofs, 1966 (Box 69)
      - Mrs. Packard's (Ms. Gould) Proofs, 1965; 3 (Box 69)
      - Correspondence--Active, 1970s-1980s (Box 69)
      - Correspondence, 1966; 2 (Box 69)
      - Manuscript, 3 (Box 70)
      - Proofs from the Series (Box 70)
      - Part I Proofs, 2 (Box 70)
      - Part II Proofs, 2 (Box 70)
      - Part III Proofs, 2 (Box 70)
      - Proofs (Mrs. Packard Proofs 2), 2 (Box 70)
      - Special articles - Philosophy
        - Proofs, 1961 (Box 70)
        - Manuscripts, 1961 (Box 70)
      - Third Programme
        - Correspondence (reaction), 1963-64 (Box 70)
    - Ram, Ram, Ram / Delinquent Chacha
      - Delinquent Chacha -Background material, 1919, 1964; 2 (Box 70)
      - Delinquent Chacha Artwork, undated (Box 70)
      - Delinquent Chacha Proofs, 1963, 1966; 3 (Box 70)
      - Delinquent Chacha Proofs and setting copy, 1966-67, undated (Box 71)
      - Delinquent Chacha Master proofs (Box 71)
      - Ram, Ram, Ram Version 4 (Indian and Sinclair material), 1963-64 (Box 71)
      - Ram, Ram, Ram Proofs, 1964 (Box 71)
    - "Put it on Account"
      - Versions 1-3 (Box 72)
      - 2nd version (Box 72)
      - 3rd version (Box 72)
      - 1st version (Box 72)
    - The New India - Penguin ed. material, 3 (Box 72)
    - Setting Material - Photographs of Chachaji, 2 (Box 72)
    - Norton Reader proofs of The Ledge Between the Streams, 1984 (Box 72)
    - New Yorker proofs of City of a Dreadful Night
    - Portrait of India - Proof, Galleys: Book I and II, undated; 2 (Box 73)
    - Portrait of India Author's Proof--Book I, 1969; 2 (Box 73)
    - Daddyji Checking material, undated; 2 (Box 73)
    - "Letter from New Delhi" manuscript, 1983 April 21 (Box 73)
    - "Learning" Manuscript, 1983 April 21; 2 (Box 73)
    - New India Manuscript and proof, returned from Viking, 1978 August 7; 3 (Box 73)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux Proofs of Daddyji, 1972; 3 (Box 74)
    - Daddyji, Author's proof, 1972; 3 (Box 74)
    - "Personal History" ("In the Force & Road of Casualty"), proofs
      Ran as "Casualties of Oxford" 8/2/93
      - New Yorker galleys, early versions?, 1993 (Box 74)
      - Reader's proofs, 1993
      - Checker's proofs - July 16 & 20, 1993 July
      - Photocopy of Ch.VI ("Time the Subtle Thief of Youth") (Box 74)
    - Revisions: R. Gandhi and The Stolen Light (Box 75)
    - R. Gandhi: Ch. 9(?) and The Mosque and the Temple (Box 75)
    - Delhi letter 1991/93 (Box 75)
    - New India Piece (Box 75)
    - India Peace Dead (Box 75)
    - Delhi Letter correspondence 1995-96 (Box 75)
    - Walking the Indian Streets (proof) (Box 75)
    - Walking the Indian Streets (setting copy) (Box 75)
    - Autobiographical Series: Illustrations (Box 75)
    - Autobiographical Series: Leonardo Society photograph
    - Daulat Ram's memories (Paternal Uncle), 1959 (Box 75)
    - Personal bibliographies and resumes (Box 75)
      Includes 1 computer disk (stored in: Box 122).
      Electronic files available through Access Services (Disk #9).
    - (Inactive) Bibliography (Box 75)
    - Scrapbooks, 2
    - Stories (unpublished)
      - Accident (Box 76)
      - Bout with John Barleycorn
        - Unfinished (Box 76)
        - Openings (Box 76)
      - Brother's Keeper (Box 76)
      - Dr. Lal (Box 76)
      - Empress of Silence (Box 76)
      - To Ghosts (Box 76)
      - Hakimji (Box 76)
      - Indians in New York (Box 76)
      - The Interview (Chacha) (Box 76)
      - Chacha -- Scenes not used, 2 (Box 76)
      - Karva Chauth (Box 77)
      - Khaval (Box 77)
      - Marriage (Box 77)
      - Paran (unfinished) (Box 77)
      - Sunny Side Up (duplicates) (Box 77)
      - Wedding, 2 (Box 77)
      - Wong (Box 77)
      - Delinquent Chacha -- final manuscript, 1966 (Box 77)
    - Articles (unpublished)
      - Arkansas Volume (Box 77)
      - Citizenship/ Various titles, 1961-1976 (Box 77)
      - Dangerous Learning (Box 77)
      - Dwight MacDonald (Box 77)
      - Family group (Box 77)
      - "Daddyji's corrections" (Box 77)
      - New Delhi Letter, 1981; 2 (Box 77)
      - New Delhi Letter, 1981-1988; 6 (Box 78)
    - Clyde Material
      Ethel Clyde's diaries are photocopies and transcripts.
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary, July 30-Nov. 4 1962 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary June 25, Feb. 4, & Aug. 9-Oct 29 1963 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary July 2-Nov. 11, 1964 (Box 79)
      - Mrs. Clyde's Interview, 1976 (Box 79)
      - Checking: Letter from Daddyji re: Mrs. Clyde, 1978 (Box 79)
      - Notes: Mrs. Clyde dictated after conversations with Daddy, 1978 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary May 4-Oct 14 & April 4, 1957 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary July 26-Oct 1, 1958 (Box 79)
      - Ethel Clyde's Diary 1959 pp. 786-832 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary Sept. 13-Nov. 6, 1959 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical series: Ethel Clyde's Diary 1958 pp. 737-785 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary Aug. 29-Oct 29, 1960 (Box 79)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diary July 7-Oct. 22, 1961 (Box 79)
      - Mrs. Clyde material, 1959 (Box 79)
      - Clyde Genealogy - Used (Box 79)
      - Checking: Mrs. Clyde's Genealogy and family history, 2 (Box 79)
      - Mrs. Clyde: miscellaneous material for Daddyji (Box 80)
      - Mrs. Clyde sources (Box 80)
      - Daddyji and Mrs. Clyde (Box 80)
      - Checking: Father and Mrs. Clyde (Box 80)
      - Checking: Mrs. Clyde Who's Who & Newspaper articles (Box 80)
      - Mrs. Clyde Diaries, 1952-1978; 4 (Box 80)
      - Mrs. Clyde Material, 1952 (Box 80)
      - Clyde file, autumn, 1952 (Box 80)
      - Checking: California Mrs. Clyde's Diary, 1952 (Box 80)
      - Ethel Clyde's Diary pp. 1-64, 1952 (Box 80)
      - Archives, mostly Mrs. Clyde, 1960 (Box 80)
      - Letters, 1961 (Box 80)
      - Ethel Clyde's diary pp. 1-64, 1952 (Box 80)
      - Mrs. Clyde, 1952; 2 (Box 80)
      - Checking: California Mrs. Clyde's Diary, 1953; 2 (Box 81)
      - Mrs. Clyde's diary, handwritten, 1954 (Box 81)
      - To be proofread: Ethel Clyde's diary pp. 199-346, 1954 (Box 81)
      - Autobiographical Series: Ethel Clyde's Diaries April 26-Oct. 1, 1955 (Box 81)
      - To be proofread: Ethel Clyde's diaries pp. 347-471, 1955 (Box 81)
      - To be proofread: Ethel Clyde's diary p. 472-585, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Autobiographical series: Ethel Clyde's diary Jan. 16 & 17, March 7-July 16, and December 23, 1956 (Box 81)
      - Mrs. Clyde's diary pp. 585a-936, 1957 (Box 81)
      - Mrs. Clyde's nephew (Box 82)
      - Ethel Clyde's diary pp. 737-785 checking (Box 82)
      - Ethel Clyde's diary pp. 585a-736 (Box 82)
      - Dr. Mehta Material (Mrs. Clyde episodes) (Box 82)
      - Checking: Steamboat Books (for Clyde family History) (Box 82)
      - Mrs. Clyde, copies of manuscripts, undated (Box 83)
      - Ethel Clyde's diaries, transcripts, 1952-1964; 11 (Box 83)
      - Archives: Mrs. Clyde, 1982, undated (Box 83)
      - Mrs. Clyde checking, last chapter, 1959 (Box 83)
      - Mrs. Clyde's medical records, 1957 (Box 83)
      - Notes -- Mrs. Clyde, 1978 (Box 83)
      - Correspondence related to Mrs. Clyde (copies), 1956-1959; 2 (Box 83)
  - Educational Records
    - Arkansas School For the Blind
      - Simla: St. Dunston's, 1948-1949 (Box 84)
      - Correspondence for Family Archives, 1958-1982 (Box 84)
        Ved to Daddyji, Autobiographical Sketch, Paul Braisted to Ved, Letter to Sir Raghaven, Letter from Ved to Daddyji
      - Original Letters, 1958-1959 (Box 84)
      - Letters and Records from Arkansas School for the Blind, 1949-1950, undated; 7 (Box 84)
      - Arkansas School for the Blind Graduation and Application to College, 1952 (Box 84)
      - Arkansas School for the Blind Student Register, 1949-1954 (Box 85)
      - Father's American Trip to Arkansas, 1952 (Box 85)
      - Arkansas Material: used scenes (Box 85)
      - Homesickness, 1952 (Box 85)
      - Daddyji and Americans, 1952 (Box 85)
      - Arkansas School History (Box 85)
    - Pomona
      Course work and files consist of typescripts and manuscripts, some corrected, including papers and essays by Ved Mehta. Other material relating to Pomona College consists of photocopies of records, transcripts and clippings.
      - Pomona Summer Session Catalogue (Box 86)
      - Pomona File; Financial Aid, etc (Box 86)
      - History 112-B 154 Vol. 1 (Box 86)
      - Writing 63, 1953-1954 (Box 86)
      - English 64 Vol. 1 (Box 86)
      - Writing, History, Government, Philosophy, 2 (Box 86)
      - Pomona College: Transcripts, Map, Student Handbook, Telephone Directory, 2 (Box 86)
      - Coursework (Box 86)
      - Pomona College Papers from Daddy's Files, 1953-1955 (Box 86)
      - Philosophy 112 (Box 86)
      - Courses, 1955-56; 5 (Box 87)
      - Checkers; Pomona Records (Box 87)
      - Pomona International Relations Club (Box 87)
      - Pomona Student Handbook (Box 87)
      - Pomona: Newspaper clippings, student life, yearbook, Pomona song (Box 88)
      - Pomona College: correspondence, list of 1958 graduates, newspaper articles, 2 (Box 88)
      - Pomona College Yearbook, 1956 (Box 88)
    - Oxford Coursework
      - Tutorials: Political science
        - Tutorials: Politics, economics, philosophy, 1956 (Box 89)
        - Political science (note cards) (Box 89)
        - Book: Political science notes (Box 89)
      - Tutorials: history [essays and notes 1956-1959]
        - English History 600-1215 (Box 89)
        - English History 600-1215 (Note Cards) (Box 89)
        - English History 1215-1485 (Box 89)
        - English History 1215-1485 (Note Cards) (Box 89)
        - English History Tudors & Stuarts (Box 89)
        - English History Tudors and Stuarts (Note Cards) (Box 89)
        - English History 18th and 19th Centuries (Note Cards) (Box 89)
        - Notebook: Cromwell Vol. 1 (Box 89)
        - Notebook: Cromwell Vol. 2 (Box 89)
        - Notebook: Cromwell Vol. 3 (Box 89)
        - Cromwell: note cards, 2 (Box 90)
        - 18th and 19th century [English] History Vol. 3 (Box 90)
        - Europe 1870-1914 (Box 90)
        - Europe Volume II 1870-1914 (Box 90)
        - European 1870-1914 (Note Cards) (Box 90)
        - Europe 1914-1939 (Box 90)
        - Constitutional Documents Vol. I (Box 90)
        - Constitutional Documents Vol. II (Box 90)
        - Constitutional Documents Vol. III (Box 90)
      - Paper Read to Leonardo Society Balliol, 1958 (Box 90)
    - Harvard Material
      - Harvard 17th century seminar (note cards), 1956-1960 (Box 90)
      - Autobiographical series, family archives: India Harvard 59-61, Babuji. Harvard volume (Box 90)
      - Harvard grad school, 1959 (Box 90)
      - Summer in India, misc. correspondence, 1959 (Box 90)
  - Engagement Diaries
    Boxes 91-92 (Engagement Diaries): Restricted until 2031.
    - Engagement Diaries, 1961-1979; 19 (Box 91)
    - Engagement Diaries, 1980-1989; 10 (Box 92)
  - Family Archives
    - Family Archives 1920s
      - Mostly parents' letters from the '20s; letter Daddyji to Brother, 1925 (Box 93)
      - Letter to Father, 1924 (Box 93)
    - Family Archives 1930s
      - Krisham letters, 1935 (Box 93)
      - Tuberculosis conference, 1936 (Box 93)
      - Krisham letters, 1936 (Box 93)
      - Family documents; Krisham's letters, 1938-1942 (Box 93)
      - Family correspondence, 1939 (Box 93)
    - Family Archives 1940s
      - California Loyalty Oath (Box 93)
      - Letter from Mr. Halder to Dr. Farrell, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Lady Wonder: Mind Reading Horse, 1947 (Box 93)
      - Letter from Father about 1947, 1982 (Box 93)
      - Emerson Institute for the Blind, Lahore and India Divided and Correspondence with other Institutes for the Blind, 1946-1948 (Box 93)
      - Family Archives 1948: Card from Usha to Ved (Box 93)